zipform.com 2018-01-09

# 

ZIPLOGIXTM PRIVACY AND SECURITY STATEMENT
Effective August 10, 2017
This document was previously updated July 25, 2013.
zipLogixTM (“we” “us” or “our”) appreciates your interest in and use of our products and services. The
protection of your privacy and the security of our products and services are important to us. We have
created this Privacy and Security Statement (“Statement”) to demonstrate our firm commitment to
privacy and so that you will be aware of the uses made of information that may be generated through
your use of our website and products and services. Please take a few minutes to read the complete
Statement.
TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT
Personal Information
Personal information is information that permits direct association with a specific individual. Personal
information, such as your name, user name, password, broker affiliation, mailing address, email
address, and phone number is either requested or required at different points during your use of our
website or products and services to complete your order, create your account and/or ensure that you
are authorized to use certain intellectual property (e.g., form libraries in zipForm®) that may be
licensed to us. Depending upon the libraries to which you request access, your current association
membership status or broker affiliation may be verified by asking you to log into other websites. You
may also enter personal information relating to yourself or others into certain fields when you use our
products and services in your real estate business. For example, you may enter personal information
relating to a client, customer, purchaser or seller into a form in zipForm® during a real estate
transaction.
Payment-related Information
Payment-related information is information used to process payments you make for products and
services made available to you. Payment-related information, such as your credit-card number and
expiration date, is required whenever a payment is necessary to complete your order for a product or
service or to create or renew your account. We use third-party payment processors for electronic
transactions and do not collect or store payment-related information.
Non-Personal Information
We also collect non-personal information. Non-personal information is aggregated information and
other information that does not permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect,
use and disclose non-personal information for any purpose except as prohibited by law. For example,
we may collect information relating to your activities on our website, your use of our products and
services and information you enter into certain fields within our products such as a zip code. If we
combine your non-personal information with your personal information, we will treat the combined
information as personal information.

Cookies and Other Technologies
Our website and some of our online products and services, email messages and advertisements may
use cookies, log files and other technologies to collect information about your use of our website,
products and services. We treat information collected by cookies, log files and other technologies as
non-personal information, except when combined with personal information or as provided by law.
We use cookies and other technologies to verify user information, to make your use of our website,
products and services more convenient and to assist in understanding your use of our website, products
and services. Most internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you prefer, you may set your
browser so that it refuses cookies or alerts you when cookies are being created on your hard drive. You
should be aware that by not accepting cookies you may impair your ability to use certain portions of
our website, products and services.
California Do Not Track Disclosures
Do Not Track is a privacy preference that users can set in their web browsers. When a user turns on
the Do Not Track signal, the browser sends a message to websites requesting them not to track the
user. We do not currently respond to Do Not Track browser settings or signals.
HOW WE USE INFORMATION
Personal Information
We use personal information in the following ways:
•   Providing the products and services: Primarily, we store and use personal information to provide
    the products and services to you and to make our products and services easier for you to use by not
    making you enter personal information more than once.
•   Managing your account: We will use your personal information to help manage your
    subscription, respond to your inquiries about the products and services, and to provide technical
    administration and support for you,
•   Product security: We use your personal information to add security to our products by printing
    your name, and your broker’s name and address, on your transaction forms in zipForm®.
•   Processing your transactions: We may also use your personal information to help you process
    your real estate transactions.
•   Sending you information: We may use your personal information to send you important
    information regarding the products or services, changes to any terms, conditions or policies or other
    administrative information.
•   Marketing from us to you: We may contact you to market or promote zipLogixTM or third party
    products or services we believe you will find useful.
•   Enhancing your experience of the products and services: We store and use personal
    information to collect information about your zipLogixTM product and service usage for internal
    business purposes, including auditing and data analysis. This helps us determine how to best
    improve our products and services and what other products and services may be valuable or of
    interest to you.
•   Anonymized data: We may aggregate or de-identify or otherwise anonymize your personal
    information. This process removes personally identifiable information to prevent the resulting

     anonymized data from being associated with any particular individual or user. Anonymized data
     is treated as non-personal information under this Privacy Policy.
Non-Personal Information
We gather non-personal information to understand and analyze trends in your use of our website,
products and services, to gather information about our user base and the real estate industry as a whole,
to administer our website, products and services and to help us determine how to improve our products,
services and advertising. We may store and use non-personal information to create, use, license and
sell general analytic databases that may provide insight into subjects including, but not limited to, real
estate market practices, industry trends and general economic conditions. We may also use this
information in our marketing and advertising services, in our creation of new products and services
and for our internal business purposes.
DISCLOSURE TO THIRD PARTIES
When you subscribe or otherwise give us personal information, we do not share that information with
third parties without your permission, other than for the limited exceptions described below:
We occasionally hire other companies to provide services on our behalf, including development,
testing, hosting, and answering customer questions about our products or services. We will provide to
those companies only the personal information necessary to enable those companies to provide such
services, and we prohibit them from using that information for any other purpose.
If you are using a multi-user edition of one of our products (such as zipForm® Broker or Team edition,
your personal information may be shared with your broker, team leader, or other users as authorized
by the primary owner of your multi-user edition. If your license to use our product or services was
provided by a third party, such as the National Association of REALTORS®, we may share certain of
your personal information with that third party for authentication purposes to confirm your right to use
the product and prevent unauthorized usage of our products and services.
When you use our products or services, you may direct us to transmit your personal information to
another service provider, such as a multiple listing service; when you direct us to transmit your
information (such as by clicking “submit”) we will transmit only the information you instruct us to
transmit and we cannot be held responsible for any errors you make in your instructions to us.
Additionally, if you have access to form libraries through your use of our products or services, your
personal information may be provided to the third parties providing such form libraries, including, but
not limited to, Associations of REALTORS®, multiple listing services and brokerages. We may also
share your personal information with these third parties to prevent unauthorized usage of our products
or services or unauthorized access to third party form libraries.
We may also provide your personal information, but not the non-public personal information you enter
into zipLogixTM products and services related to your clients and customers, to our parent company
and its subsidiaries to offer other products or services that may be valuable or interesting to you; we
do not provide your personal information to other third parties for marketing purposes.
We will disclose personal information without notice only if required to do so by law or in the good
faith belief that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights or property of zipLogixTM.

We may provide non-personal information to third parties for general analytic purposes related to real
estate market practices, industry trends and general economic conditions. If we are involved in a merger
or are acquired, then all or substantially all of our assets may be transferred to the acquirer. In such a
transaction, user information including personal and non-personal information could be among the
transferred assets. In such an event, you will be notified via a prominent notice on our website of any
change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have
regarding your personal information. Your information will remain protected by this policy in
accordance with its terms.
ADVERTISEMENTS AND LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES
We may sell advertising space to third parties on our website or in our products and services, which is
usually in the form of a graphic link to the Internet site of the advertiser (a “banner advertisement”).
We may also provide links to third party websites through other methods. These linked sites are not
under our control and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the contents of any such linked
website, or any link contained in any linked website and any personal information you provide will be
collected by, and controlled by the privacy policy of, that third party. If you have concerns about the
privacy practices of a third-party website to which we link, you should direct those concerns to the
third party responsible for that website. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS POLICY DOES NOT
ADDRESS THE PRIVACY OR INFORMATION PRACTICES OF ANY THIRD PARTIES,
INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, OUR PARENT COMPANY OR ITS SUBSIDIARIES.
Third-party advertising on our website is pre-selected by us or our parent company or its subsidiaries.
zipLogixTM does not employ behavioral advertising or otherwise allow third-party advertisers to track
your activity or display advertising targeted to your browsing history or other online activities.
SOCIAL MEDIA
We maintain profiles on social media websites such as Facebook, Twitter and YouTube, and our
website links to those social media profiles. When you interact with our profiles on social media, you
will be governed by the terms of use and any information you submit will be covered by the privacy
policy of that social media provider. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content found
on the website of these social media providers beyond our own profiles. We do not collect or use any
data gathered from your interactions with our social media profiles.
SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
For website security purposes and to ensure that our products and services remain available to all users,
our servers employ industry-standard methods to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized
attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorized attempts to upload
information or change information on our servers are strictly prohibited and may be punishable by law,
including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure
Protection Act of 1996. We use technical and organizational security measures in order to protect the
data we have under our control against loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or
destruction. Inside the company, data is stored in password-controlled servers with limited
access. Although we take measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, no
transmission of data over the Internet is 100% secure so we cannot guarantee that information we
collect or store will be protected from all unauthorized access or use.

You also have a significant role in protecting your information. Do not share your password or allow
others to use your account. It is good practice for you to change your password regularly.
USE OF THE SITE BY CHILDREN
Our website, products and services are not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen (13), and
we request that such individuals do not provide personal information through our website, products or
services. We do not knowingly collect information from individuals under the age of thirteen (13) and
if we learn that we have collected personal information from such an individual, we will delete that
information promptly on becoming aware of such collection.
CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS’ PRIVACY RIGHTS
California law permits users who are California residents to request from us a disclosure that (1)
identifies the categories of Personal Information that we share with our parent company, subsidiaries,
or third parties for marketing purposes and (2) provides the names of those companies with whom we
share such information. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain a copy of this disclosure,
please mail a written request to zipLogixTM LLC, Attn: California Privacy Disclosure, 18070 15 Mile
Road, Fraser, Michigan 48026.
INTERNATIONAL USERS
We do not intentionally collect information from users located outside the United States, Mexico or
Canada. All information collected or stored by us is kept on servers located within the United States.
If you are a user located outside the United States, when you enter your information, both personal and
non-personal, into any of our products and services you consent to your information being transferred
to and stored on servers located within the United States.
REVIEW/CORRECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
We market and sell several products and services. Our products and services that collect and use
personal information provide, where appropriate, a method that allows you to inspect whether your
personal information is correct and current. To reduce the possibility that some subscribers may
attempt to share their access to and use of our products and services with non-subscribers, some of
your information - once it is entered - may not be directly changeable by you.
If you wish to review, correct or update any personal information about you collected through our
website or through your use of our products and services, please click on SALES, or write to us at:
zipLogixTM LLC, 18070 15 Mile Road, Fraser, Michigan 48026.
DELETION PRACTICES
If you choose to delete your account, or your account becomes inactive (for example when you do not
renew your subscription), information associated with your account may remain stored on our servers
for a period of time that can vary subject to our data retention policies and other legal obligations. Our
data retention policies for different types of data are set forth in our Terms of Use, which can be found
here.

OTHER TERMS
Your use of the zipLogixTM website and our products and services is governed by our Terms of Use,
which can be found here.
We are committed to making our website and our products accessible for all our users. Our Website
Accessibility statement can be found here.
OPT OUT
To opt out of having your personal information provided to our parent company, its subsidiaries or
third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please click on OPT OUT, or write to us at:
zipLogixTM, LLC, 18070 15 Mile Road, Fraser, Michigan 48026, Attn: REFN Third Party Opt Out
Request. We will process your request as quickly as possible. You may not opt out of receiving
communications from us regarding administrative information for the products or services since this
information may be important to your use of the products or services. Please note that if you opt-out
as described above, we will not be able to remove personal information about you from the databases
of third parties with which we have already shared personal information about you prior to processing
your opt-out request. If you wish to cease receiving e-mails from third parties, please contact the third
parties directly or utilize any opt-out mechanisms set forth in their respective privacy policies or e-
mails to you.
CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT
We reserve the right to alter this Statement as our business needs require. In the event we make any
material changes to this Statement, we will notify you by updating the Statement’s effective date and
indicating the previous effective date. As you use our website, products and services, we encourage
you to periodically check back with this Statement for changes that we may make. Your continued use
of our website and/or our products and services will constitute your agreement to any changes we make
and if you do not agree with a change, please refrain from using our website and/or our products and
services.
CONTACT INFORMATION
We welcome your comments regarding our website, our products and services and this Statement. To
contact us, please click on SALES, or write to us at: zipLogixTM, LLC, 18070 15 Mile Road, Fraser,
Michigan 48026.
